翻译 NETFLIX　校对 皮带断了
特效 小布　后期&压制 Jason肖
恶魔城
第三季 第７集
我还以为今天要去看军械库的其余地方呢
I thought we were going to look at the rest of the armory today.
如果现在是今天的话
If it is, in fact, today.
浩隆不适应早上
Taka isn't good at mornings.
而且现在比早上还早
And this is some extra morning.
太早了 还是昨天呢
It is so much morning that it's actually still yesterday.
你们不该熬夜探索城堡的
Well, you shouldn't have stayed up so late exploring the castle.
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
我们想看移动城堡的引擎
We wanted to see the engine that moved the castle.
能修好吗
Can it ever be fixed?
也许吧
Maybe.
但那需要很长时间 而我们还有别的事要做
But it will take a very long time, and there are other things to do.
跟我来
Follow me.
还有什么事比那更重要
What could be more important than that?
太多了
So many things.
我哪都不去 浩隆
I'm not going anywhere, Taka.
城堡已经完成了最后一次移动
The castle's moved for the last time.
有一些地方我需要守卫
I have places to guard.
魔法灯笼
Magic lanterns!
是闪电 不是魔法
Lightning. Not magic.
你把闪电装进灯笼里
You put lightning into lamps
还说不是魔法
and you tell us it's not magic?
真的不是
It's really not.
早在公元前两百年 帕提亚人就把闪电存进了罐子里
The Parthians were storing lightning in jars two hundred years before Christ.
这是贝尔蒙特密室
This is the Belmont Hold.
一个家族的最终存储库
The final repository of a family
他们世世代代只学习如何做一件事
who spent generations learning how to do one thing:
杀怪物
Kill monsters.
包括吸血鬼
Including vampires.
来吧
Shall we?
你们想学关于杀吸血鬼的所有知识
You want to learn everything about killing vampires?
那是贝尔蒙特家族的毕生研究
The Belmonts made it their lives,
而且都写下来了
and they wrote it all down.
你们了解吸血鬼解剖结构吗
Do you understand the anatomy of a vampire?
用尖锐的东西刺入他们心脏
You put a stabby thing into their heart
他们就灰飞烟灭
and they go boom.
比这要复杂一点
It's a little more complicated than that.
但算一个好开头
Good start, though.
那...人呢
What about... people?
我相信你们知道怎么杀人
I'm fairly sure you know how to kill people.
阿町有许多人类战奴
Cho had many human warrior slaves.
也许我们根本应付不过来
Maybe more than we can take on our own.
我们可以看看战术
Well, we can look at tactics.
还有闪电灯笼呢
And the lightning lamps.
闪电也能做武器吗
Can lightning be a weapon, too?
你能用闪电一下子杀死很多人吗
Could you make lightning kill a lot of people at once?
从小事做起 好吗
Let's start small, shall we?
当然 我们只是担心很多事
Of course. We are just worried about a lot of things.
你一直很善良 我们无比感恩
You're being incredibly kind, and we are very grateful.
我知道你们担心
I know you're worried.
浩隆 你必须明白
Taka, you need to understand
我不只是在传授杀人的方法
that I'm not just passing on ways to murder people.
我明白
I do.
只是我们的处境十分不利
It's just that the odds are so stacked against us.
我夜不能寐
I can't sleep.
所以才整夜在城堡里走来走去
That's why I was wandering around the castle all night.
珠美只是为了陪我
Sumi was just keeping me company.
好吧 好吧 但是…
All right, all right. But...
你们必须明白
you do need to understand.
我和你们分享这些信息
I'm sharing all of this with you
为的是让你们记住并传承下去
so that you'll remember it and pass it on.
不只是战争部分的内容
Not just the war-making.
而是全部
Everything.
我觉得特雷弗·贝尔蒙特会喜欢
I think Trevor Belmont would like the idea
武装新一代怪物猎人的点子
of equipping a new generation of monster hunters.
不准跑
No running!
我跟你说过无数次了 我不准孩子
I've told you a thousand times I won't have children
像野狗一样在我的镇上到处乱窜
running like wild dogs through my town.
尤其是你 我最少说了20次 不是吗
And I've told you, in particular, more than twenty times, haven't I?
是不是 孩子
Haven't I, boy?
你一大早过来
And you're here first thing in the morning
是因为你喜欢最新鲜的苹果 是吗
because you like the freshest apples, aren't you?
嗯 我猜也是
Mmm. I thought so.
你想知道一个秘密吗
Would you like to know a secret?
如果你穿过后方的空地进入树林
If you go into the woods through the back field
并沿着小路走到岔口
and follow the path until the fork,
选择有棵大树的那条路 就是你们都说它像一张愤怒的脸的那棵
and you go down the way with the big tree that you all say looks like an angry face,
然后淌过小溪
and you go over the creek,
经过你父母说不该去的那地方...
past the point the way your parents say you shouldn't go...
对吧
Right?
我恰好知道 在那后面的空地上有一棵苹果树
I happen to know there's an apple tree in the clearing after that.
树是我的
It's my apple tree,
谁也不允许去那里
and nobody's allowed to go there.
所以 如果你保证不告诉任何人
So, if you promise not to tell a soul where you're going...
就能去摘三个苹果
Go and get yourself three apples.
还有 不准再跑了
And no more running.
你起得真早
You're up early.
要做的事情太多 可能来不及
Lots to do. Probably not enough time to do it.
听说你昨天跟贝尔纳德斯和贝尔蒙特喝酒了
I'm told you were drinking with Belnades and Belmont yesterday.
我是大名人 而且他们想看看见过厕纸的人
I am extremely famous and they wanted to meet someone who'd seen toilet paper.
厕纸是什么鬼东西
What the fuck is toilet paper?
中国特产 早上好 法官
It's Chinese. Good morning, Judge.
厕纸
Toilet paper.
这可不是应该出现在修道院的东西
Not an obvious thing to find in a church.
萨拉院长
Uh, Prior Sala?
Prior Sala!
你好 圣日耳曼
Oh, good. Saint Germain.
我有个问题 院长
A question, Prior.
恐怕我们今早很忙
We are quite busy this morning, I'm afraid.
这本书 你认识吗
Th-This book. Do you recognize it?
不认识
I don't.
真的吗
Really?
因为修道院出现这本书很不寻常
Because it's an unusual book to find in a church.
众所周知 老院长们藏过一些
Old priories are known to find themselves
不同寻常的古书
storing old and unusual books.
没错
Indeed so.
但有人在最近看过这本书 萨拉
But someone recently read this book, Sala.
然后撕掉了其中一段
After which they tore a section out.
很多书都有损毁
Many of these books are damaged.
我不明白你为何如此激动
I don't see why this should excite you so.
因为撕痕尚未变黄 萨拉
Because the tears haven't yellowed, Sala.
这一段是在过去几个月里撕掉的
The section was removed within the last few months.
边缘的烟灰还没散 而且…
The soot on the edges is still loose. And...
我想知道…
And I wonder...
是谁从你的收藏中选了这本书
who selected this book from your collection?
我看不出来我为什么应该对这本书感兴趣
I fail to see why this should interest me.
因为撕掉的那段记载着让人从地狱…
Because the missing section involves methods and processes
归来的方法和过程
for returning people from Hell.
也许有人只是单纯地撕掉那几页
Perhaps someone simply pulled out those pages
用来擦屁股了
to wipe their backside with.
我知道东方人用纸擦屁股
I understand they use paper for that in the Orient.
这本书是由两百年前一位锻造师写的
This book was written by a forgemaster some two hundred years ago,
一位不走寻常路的疯狂锻造师
an insane forgemaster who did not practice in the usual way.
有任何德古拉的信息吗
Is there any mention of Dracula?
没有 但这不是重点...
No. But you miss the point...
那你最好回去工作
Then you had better get back to work.
萨拉
Sala.
你曾让我不要把你当成疯子
You told me not to treat you as if you were mad.
别让我失望
Do not disappoint me.
早上好 锻造师先生
Good morning, Sir Forgemaster.
你认识我吗
You know me?
我闻到你的气味了
I smell you.
你会发现 这里没有鲜活的肉体供你杀害和锻造
You'll find no fresh bodies to kill and forge here.
这里就你一个人吗
You're alone here?
完全没错
Entirely.
一个人的村子可不多见
It's not every day you see a one-person village.
很久以前 这里曾经人满为患
Once upon a time, you may have found it quite over-full.
十人住一栋房子 到处是吵嚷的孩子
Ten people to a house. Screaming kids everywhere.
太拥挤了
It was teeming.
说真的 有时候我觉得这样更好
Honestly? Sometimes I like it a little better now.
是你干的吗
Did you do this?
不 天啊
Oh, no. Oh, God, no.
完全超出了我的能力
Quite outside my powers.
前面50公里处有一个镇子
There's a town thirty miles up the road.
其实…
Well...
那里更像个监狱
more of a prison, really.
既然那是我要去的方向
Since that is the direction I'm headed,
也许你能给一个旅行者和同修
perhaps you'd give a traveler and fellow practitioner
一个善意的警告
a friendly warning?
你也能闻出我的气味吗
You can smell me, too?
我能看出来
I see you.
镇子被一个魔法师控制着
The town is run by a magician.
他梦想用奴隶
He has dreams of a city,
建造一座城市
a slave population to build it.
所以他扫荡了周围的村庄
So he swept up the surrounding villages,
把他们的灵魂烧成灰烬
cooked their souls down to ash...
把他们变成了蝼蚁
turned them into ants.
让他们吃屎
Make them eat shit
和搬砖
and stack bricks.
但是...你还在这
But... you're still here.
是啊
Yes.
所以 你任由这个魔法师抓走了你的邻居
So, you let this magician take your neighbors.
我想知道为什么
I wonder why.
当然了 除非你根本不是你假装出来的样子
Unless, of course, you're not quite what you pass yourself off as.
我..就是
Oh... I am.
我只是没有以前那么强大了
I'm just not as strong as I was.
这种生活要付出代价 锻造师
This life takes a toll, Forgemaster.
是的
It does.
我叫艾萨克
I am Isaac.
米兰达
Miranda.
你能自保 但是…
You were able to protect yourself, but...
我能把他们从我身边吓跑
I was able to frighten them away from me.
但魔法力量已经很弱了
But the magic is thin now.
我无法帮助任何人
I couldn't do a thing for anyone else.
我只能眼睁睁看着
I had to just watch.
那个魔法师没回来找你吗
The magician never came back for you?
他没有理由回来
He has no reason to.
我现在也能自保
I can still defend myself,
他没办法转化我
he wouldn't be able to turn me.
我对他来说有多少价值呢
And how much use would I be to him, anyway?
他已经有了所需要的一切
He has what he needs.
那个狗日的疯子
The mad bastard!
在这里建一个城邦
Building a city-state here.
总有一天 施第里尔人会冲进围绕他的城市
One day the Styrians will punch through the cities that enclose them
蜂拥到全国各地
and swarm across the country.
我要去施第里尔
I'm going to Styria.
天啊 为什么
Why, for God's sake?
那里有我要杀的人
I have people to kill there.
那你需要更多黑暗生物
Well, you will need more of them.
而且骑马还要两星期才能到
And Styria is still a good two weeks' ride from here.
我被人背叛了
I was betrayed.
我对此无能为力
I could not do a thing.
我说的魔法师
The magician I spoke of
有一面传送镜 艾萨克
has a transmission mirror, Isaac.
真的吗
Really?
一个非常高非常宽的镜子
One that is unusually tall and wide,
一次能传送很多人
and can transmit many people at once.
当然了 想获得那样的宝贝
Of course, to obtain such a treasure,
你得杀光镇上所有人
you will have to kill everyone in that town,
让魔法师失去防卫
so that the magician has no defense.
从而将所有人
Thereby converting the entire population
转化为更多的黑暗生物
into more of your night creatures,
为你装备一支完整的军队
equipping you with a full army
去施第里尔复仇
to take your revenge in Styria.
对了 我早该告诉你 我非常生气
Yes, I probably should have mentioned that I am quite mad.
杀光他们吧 帅气的锻造师
Oh, kill them all, pretty forgemaster.
他们会为此感谢你的
They'll thank you for it.
而且他们会感谢你
And they'll thank you
把他们变成了
for turning them into instruments of revenge
向人类复仇的工具
against the human race.
去救我的老邻居吧 然后夺取你的战利品
Go and save my old neighbors, and take your reward.
那会让一位疲惫不堪的老同修高兴不已
It would please a tired old colleague in your art,
而是那才是正义
and it would be justice.
这世上有比施第里尔的吸血鬼
There are worse things in the world
更糟的东西 艾萨克
than vampires in Styria, Isaac.
有比背叛...更糟的东西
There are worse things... than betrayal.
看
Watch.
抓到他们了
Got them.
现在怎么办
Now what?
我们去质问他们
I suppose we question them.
我们只需要其中一个就够了
We only need one of them for that.
而且我们不想惊动修道院
And we don't need the alarm raised in the priory.
你有什么建议吗
Do you have a suggestion?
交给我处理吧
Let me take care of it.
自从这件事与魔法和奇怪的符号扯上关系
I've felt bloody useless ever since all of this
我就觉得自己很没用
became about magic and weird symbology.
-你确定吗  -确定
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
我是个容易满足的简单男人
I'm a simple man with simple pleasures.
我真的喜欢遇到职业杀手
Oh, I do like meeting a professional killer.
这种握法 每次都能暴露身份
And that grip gives it away every time.
这是什么
What's this?
我找到故意破坏公物的人了
I've found your vandal.
是一个很淘气的修道士
He's a very naughty monk.
我们抓到他在一栋房子一侧刻一个符号
We caught him carving a symbol into the side of a home.
就是我们在前门看到的那个符号
The one we saw at the front gates.
在村子各处都能看到那个符号
The one seen in a few places around the village.
那个符号带着令人不安的含义
One with a troubling set of meanings.
告诉法官那个符号代表什么
Tell the Judge what the symbol means.
去死吧
Fuck you to death.
和我说话的时候放尊重点 修道士
Keep a civil fucking tongue in your head when you're addressing me, monk.
我什么都不会说
I'm telling you nothing.
你们不能把我关在这 你们屁都做不了
You can't keep me here. You can't do a thing.
我们可以直接杀了你
We could just kill you.
真不敢相信我居然试着对你客气
I can't believe I tried to be nice to you.
那个符号有一组含义 合起来就是
The symbol has a set of meanings that, taken together,
"死亡和转化"
mean death and transformation.
他们在谋划一些魔法本质的事
They're planning something magical in nature.
你觉得这是个计划吗
And you think this is a plan?
萨拉和他的修道士
Sala and his people are intending
打算对这个镇子采取某种行动
to take some kind of action against the town?
我可以确定
I'm certain of it.
那 告诉我具体是什么行动
Well, tell me exactly what action.
我并不是很清楚
I do not exactly know.
但他很清楚
But he does.
还有 圣日耳曼在修道院里
And Saint Germain is inside the priory.
昨晚他知道了我们的怀疑
He shared our suspicions last night.
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠